Elvin Abduyev







PROFILE

Hello, my name is Elvin Abduyev. I am currently a software developer at IBAR in Baku, Azerbaijan. I did my master at the University of Bonn, Germany with a Specialist Program in Computer Science. I am fluent in English, Turkish and Azerbaijan languages, and have good communication skills. I have also some Russian and German skills. I am highly organized, task oriented and work well in a team environment. I am open for new technologies and always learning.



EDUCATION

University of Bonn

Master of Science (MSc) Oct 2011 - Aug 2014

Master of Science degree with a Specialist Program in Computer Science. Full scholarship within the "The ministry of Education of the Azerbaijan Republic in cooperation with DAAD" during 2011-2013



Bachelor of Science (BSc) Sep 2006 - Jun 2010



PRO SKILLS

PHP

Java	
Spring)
Hibernate)
MVC)
RESTful)
SQL)
Git / GitHub)
JQuery)
Bootstrap)
C#)
ASP.NET)
HTML5 & CSS3)
Android)
Python)
AngularJS)
React Native)
JavaScript)



+49-1573-061-88-58





Rochusstr. 375, Köln, Germany, 50827



WORK EXPERIENCE

JAVA DEVELOPER

Feb 2020 - PRESENT

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Oct 2018 - Jan 2020

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Sep 2017 - Oct 2018

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

May 2015 - Sep 2017

Arvato Systems, Cologne

Optimizing and maintaining advertisement engine using Java, Hibernate technologies. Adding new functionalities and dealing with

International Bank of Azerbaijan

Development of new features using Java and RESTful web services with Scrum methodology, product maintenance and full customer support for IBAM product.

Xalq Bank, Baku

Development of new features using Java and RESTful web services, product maintenance and full customer support for IB product and customer requests.

Huawei Technologies, Baku

Worked on CBS and CRM sides of the Billing System, working on SOAP and RESTful services and full customer support for Bill Run process.



PROJECTS

Web Developer

Redesigned and maintained the front end functionality of a NOPA project using HTML, CSS and JavaScript and find bugs and solve in backend of the website using PHP.

eLibrary System

The system developed for the students of the academy, where they can make a booking online or read the book online used Java, Spring Boot, MVC, Hibernate, Bootstrap, jQuery, GIT, Apache Tomcat, MySQL. The project is developed by a team of 3 people working with Scrum methodology.

Course Registration System

The system developed for the students and lecturers of the course for registration desired courses and managing the courses used Java, Spring Boot, MVC, Hibernate, Bootstrap, jQuery, GIT, Apache Tomcat, MySQL. The project is developed by a team of 2 people.

Integration of Payment Systems

The system is developed for integrating client's internal payment system to our Internet Banking product used Java, Spring Boot, Hibernate, SOAP web services. The project is developed by a team of 5 people working with Scrum methodology.

Cafeteria Website

The system developed for the employees of the bank for ordering daily, weekly lunches after login to the website using employee ID used Java, Spring, MVC, Hibernate, Bootstrap, jQuery, GIT, Apache Tomcat, MySQL. The project is developed by a team of 2 people.



AWARDS AND CERTIFICATES

OCA Oracle

2019 Oracle Certified Associate (Java SE 8 Programmer I)

Employee of year Huawei Technologies CO., Ltd **Excellent Performance Award**

2016